# Shuai Zha – Curriculum Vitae

Address Department of Astronomy,

AlbaNova University Center Stockholm University

SE-106 91 Stockholm SWEDEN

Mobile Phone Email Homepage

+46 732447310 shuai.zha@astro.su.se joshuashzha.github.io

## Personal Profile

I am currently a postdoctoral researcher in the Department of Astronomy, Stockholm University, Sweden. I mainly work on developing a hydrodynamics code with neutrino transport to simulate stellar collapse and explosion. I also work on the evolution of super-asymptotic-giant-branch stars as progenitors of electron-capture supernovae.

## Position

2019- Postdoctoral researcher, Department of Astronomy, Stockholm University

#### Education

2015-2019 Ph.D. in Physics - the Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

Supernovae simulation and stellar evolution

2012-2015 M.Sc. in Physics - Fudan University, Shanghai

Sum-frequency spectroscopy with femtosecond laser

2008-2012 B.Sc. in Physics - Fudan University, Shanghai

#### **Publications**

First and second author:

1. Evolution of ONeMg Core in Super-AGB Stars towards Electron-Capture Supernovae: Effects of Updated Electron-Capture Rate

<u>Shuai Zha</u>, Shing-Chi Leung, Toshio Suzuki, Ken'ichi Nomoto *Astrophysical Journal* **886**, 22 (2019); arXiv:1907.04184

 $2. \ \ Accretion-Induced\ Collapse\ of\ Dark\ Matter\ Admixed\ White\ Dwarfs-II:\ Rotation\ and\ Gravitational-wave\ Signals$ 

<u>Shuai Zha</u>, Shing-Chi Leung, Ming-Chung Chu, Lap-Ming Lin *Astrophysical Journal* **883**, 13 (2019); arXiv:1908.05150

3. Accretion-Induced Collapse of Dark Matter Admixed White Dwarfs - I : Formation of Low-mass Neutron Stars

Shing-Chi Leung, <u>Shuai Zha</u>, Ming-Chung Chu, Lap-Ming Lin, Ken'ichi Nomoto *Astrophysical Journal* **884**, 9 (2019); arXiv:1908.05102

4. Electron capture rates in  $^{20}$ Ne for a forbidden transition to the ground state of  $^{20}$ F relevant to final evolution of high density O-Ne-Mg cores

Toshio Suzuki, Shuai Zha, Shing-Chi Leung, Ken'ichi Nomoto

Astrophysical Journal 881, 64 (2019); arXiv:1905.10400

5. Gravitational-Wave and Neutrino Signals from Core-Collapse Supernovae with QCD Phase Transition

**Shuai Zha**, Shing-Chi Leung, Lap-Ming Lin, and Ming-Chung Chu *JPS Conf. Proc.*, **20**, 011053 (2018)

6. Surface pH and Ion Affinity at the Alcohol-Monolayer/Water Interface Studied by Sum- Frequency Spectroscopy

Yu-Chieh Wen, Shuai Zha, Chuanshan Tian, and Yuen-Ron Shen

The Journal of Physical Chemistry C, 120, 28 (2016)

7. Unveiling Microscopic Structures of Charged Water Interfaces by Surface-Specific Vibrational Spectroscopy

Yu-Chieh Wen, <u>Shuai Zha</u>, Xing Liu, Shanshan Yang, Pan Guo, Guosheng Shi, Haiping Fang, Yuen-Ron Shen, and Chuanshan Tian

Phys. Rev. Lett., 116, 016101 (2016)

#### Co-author:

8. Constraints on the chemical enrichment history of the Perseus Cluster of galaxies from high-resolution X-ray spectroscopy

Aurora Simionescu et. al. (36 authors including Shuai Zha)

Mon. Notices Royal Astron. Soc., 483, 1701 (2018)

9. Carbon nanodots featuring efficient FRET for two-photon photodynamic cancer therapy with a low fs laser power density

Jing Wang, Zehui Zhang, <u>Shuai Zha</u>, Yinyan Zhu, Peiyi Wu, Benjamin Ehrenberg, and Ji-Yao Chen

Biomaterials, 35, 9372 (2014)

#### Seminar talks

Oct. 2018 ASIAA, Lunch talk, Taipei, Taiwan

Evolution of Super-AGB Stars Towards Accretion-Induced Collapse

Jul. 2018 Kavli IPMU, APEC seminar, Tokyo, Japan

Correlated Gravitational-wave and Neutrino Signal from Accretion-Induced Collapse of White Dwarfs

Jul. 2016 Kavli IPMU, APEC seminar, Tokyo, Japan

Accretion Induced Collapse of White Dwarf and its Possible Signals

## Conference presentations

May 2019 Oral, Electron-Capture-Initiated Stellar Collapse, Lorentz Center, Leiden, The Netherlands

Nov. 2018 Oral, CoCoNuT Meeting 2018, CEA Saclay, Paris, France

Oct. 2018 Oral, The 8th East Asian Numerical Astrophysics Meeting, NCKU, Tainan, Taiwan

Sep. 2018 Poster, Sixth Annual GMT Community Science Meeting, Honolulu, Hawaii, United States

Feb. 2017 Poster, Quarks and Compact Stars, YITP, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan

Jul. 2016 Oral, 10th JGX Astrophysics Meeting, Xiamen University, Xiamen, Fujian

## Research experience

2017-2018 Kavli IPMU, the University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan

 ${\bf Collaborative\ research\ with\ Prof.\ Ken'ichi\ Nomoto\ on\ Evolution\ of\ Super-AGB\ stars\ towards\ Electron-Capture\ Supernova$ 

## Teaching experience

2015-2019 **Teaching assistant** General Physics, Astronomy, Introduction to Astrophysics

2012-2015 Teaching assistant University Physics, Semiconductor Physics, Nonlinear Optics

## **Professional Activities**

Feb. 2019 Organizer of supernova mini-workshop in CUHK, Hong Kong

## Awards

Sep. 2017 Global Scholarship Programme for Research Excellence, CUHK

Sep. 2012 Entrance Scholarship for fresh graduate student, Fudan University

## Programming Language

Fortran, C, matlab, Python, LATEX